What would make you happy?
什么能让你快乐呢？
Really happy?
真正的快乐？
A nice holiday, lazing on a tropical beach?
一个美好的假期，在热带海滩上悠闲地躺着？
Maybe a blowout meal with friends at a swanky restaurant?
也许是和朋友们在一家豪华的餐厅吃一顿大餐？
Or possibly splashing out on a pair of the latest designer jeans?
或者可能是挥霍一笔钱买一双最新的名牌牛仔裤？
All these pleasures cost money so does that mean we need lots of cash to feel good or does the old saying 'money can't buy happiness' still ring true?
所有这些乐趣都需要花钱，那么这是否意味着我们需要很多钱才能感觉良好，还是那句古老的谚语“金钱买不来幸福”仍然正确呢？
This well-worn adage has been put to the test by scientists in Canada.
这句老掉牙的格言已经被加拿大的科学家们进行了验证。
They found that when used in the right way, money can bring us happiness.
他们发现，当以正确的方式使用时，金钱可以给我们带来幸福。
They discovered that when you use money to free up time, by paying someone to do your chores for example, you are happier.
他们发现，当你用金钱来腾出时间时，比如付钱让别人帮你做家务，你会更快乐。
In an experiment, individuals reported greater higher life satisfaction if they used $40 to save time rather than spend it on material goods such as a new pair of shoes.
在一项实验中，一些人报告说，如果他们用40美元来节省时间，而不是把钱花在像一双新鞋这样的物质商品上，他们的生活满意度会更高。
But surprisingly, the researchers found that fewer than a third of individuals spent money to buy themselves time each month.
但令人惊讶的是，研究人员发现，每月花钱为自己买时间的人不到三分之一。
In our hectic lives time is one thing we seem to be short of.
在我们忙碌的生活中，时间似乎是我们所缺少的东西之一。
People are reporting a 'time famine', where they get stressed over the daily demands on their time.
人们称这是“时间饥荒”，他们会因为日常对时间的需求而感到压力。
Psychologists say stress over lack of time causes lower well-being and contributes to anxiety and insomnia.
心理学家说，对时间不足的压力会导致幸福感降低，并会引发焦虑和失眠。
But in many countries now, as incomes are rising, there is an option to buy more time.
但现在在许多国家，随着收入的增加，人们可以选择购买更多的时间。
This can be through hiring a cleaner to clean your house or outsourcing your ironing to someone else – giving us valuable extra hours to do the things we want to do.
这可以通过雇一个清洁工来打扫你的房子，或者把你的熨烫工作外包给别人来实现——这给了我们宝贵的额外时间去做我们想做的事情。
And in many forward-thinking companies, staff are given the opportunity to buy more time off or work flexibly.
而且在许多有前瞻性思维的公司里，员工有机会购买更多的休假时间或者灵活工作。
Professor Dunn, who worked with colleagues at Harvard Business School, Maastricht University and Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, says that "money can in fact buy time.
邓恩教授与哈佛商学院、马斯特里赫特大学和阿姆斯特丹自由大学的同事一起进行了研究，他说：“事实上，金钱可以买到时间。
And it buys time pretty effectively... and so my take home message is, 'think about it, is there something you hate doing that fills you with dread and could you pay somebody else to do that for you?' If so, then science says that's a pretty good use of money."
而且它相当有效地买到了时间......所以我的关键信息是，‘想一想，有没有什么你讨厌做的、让你充满恐惧的事情，你能不能付钱让别人来为你做呢？’如果有，那么从科学角度来说，这是对金钱的合理利用。”
I would agree that buying more time makes me feel happier and more relaxed.
我同意购买更多的时间会让我感觉更快乐、更放松。
But making time a priority over making money does come at a price; you have less cash to spend on the things you now have time to do.
但是把争取时间放在比赚钱更优先的位置确实是有代价的；在现在有时间做的事情上面，你可以花的钱会更少。
However there's another old saying that 'life is short and time is swift' so there's no time to waste and there's more to life than doing tedious housework!
然而，还有另一句古老的谚语说“人生苦短，时光飞逝”，所以没有时间可以浪费，而且生活中还有比做乏味的家务更多的事情要做！